Julian Cohen

Software maker and leader

julian@juco.co.uk | 07860 902703 | http://juco.co.uk





🌘 github.com/juco stackoverflow.com/users/1477466/juco in linkedin.com/in/cohenjulian/





ABOUT ME

Passionate about all things technology. With over 12 years industry experience, having overseen numerous projects through from inception to completion. Experience gained as a software developer as well as development leader - always striving to implement the best solution with the right tools. Extensive knowledge across the full spectrum of software creation, from the frontend through to the underlying operating system.

EXPERIENCE

Head of Technology → Technical Director

Groundsure

Dec 2016 - present

- Sitting on the board of directors, settings the company direction and overseeing the product & technology budget
- Hands on, building frontend applications with React and backend API's in Node.js
- Rebuilt underlying job layer in Ruby whilst embracing AWS technologies such as Dynamo DB, SQS, EC2, S3, Cloudwatch

Lead Developer → Head of development

Pure360

April 2013 - Dec 2016

- Lead a rebuild of the core web application using Angular, NodeJS, Scala and Ruby
- Managed two 7 developer scrum teams based in the UK and remotely in Romania
- · Making the architectural decisions and ensuring best practices were implemented and followed

Linux sysadmin → Senior developer

Claromentis

Dec 2009 - April 2013

- Developing market leading Intranet software on the LAMP stack
- Responsibile for building a team of in-house full-stack developers to replace Russian outsourcing company
- Managed a project to move all servers from dedicated Windows servers to cloud based Linux hosts

TECHNICAL SKILLS

JS Frontend

- Javascript es6, functional programming
- CSS Grid, Flexbox
- · React. Redux
- TDD (jest, mocha & chai)
- Webpack, Parcel and babel
- · PostCSS, Sass, Less
- Sketch

Backend

- Node JS express
- Ruby sinatra, Rails
- PHP laravel
- · MongoDB, MySQL
- RESTful API's

🐧 Devops

- Linux Ubuntu, Debian, Gentoo, Arch
- TravisCI
- Docker
- AWS
- · Continuous integration & deployment

EDUCATION

University of Portsmouth

First class

BSc (Hons) Computer Network Management and Design

Chichester College

Distinction

National Diploma in Computer Networking

QUALIFICATIONS

PHP Zend certification

Feb 2013

NVQ Leadership and Management

Sept 2014